Norman Corwin Papers
Norman Corwin Papers
- Productions of Corwin
  - Radio programs, individual
    - The Moat Farm Murder, Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 1 #18
      - Recording
        Presented over CBS on July 18, 1944, as the 18th program of the first COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series. Charles Laughton performed the role of Herbert Dougal, from whose actual confession to a murder the program was adapted. Elsa Lanchester (Mrs. Laughton) performed the role of Cecile Dougal. The score was written and composed by Bernard Herrmann. Published as one of the plays in UNTITLED AND OTHER RADIO DRAMAS.
        - The Moat Farm Murder [disc 1 of 2], 07/18/1944; corwin_0110; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 2)
          On the sleeve's label is written that there is additional data in Envelope 87. On the disc's label there is a note "Matched set B", it is unclear what "set B" refers to.
        - The Moat Farm Murder [disc 2 of 2], 07/18/1944; corwin_0111; Lacquer discs/acetates
          On the sleeve's label is written that there is additional data in Envelope 87.
      - Script (87), 1944; final broadcast script; includes two permissions requests (Box 19)
    - Movie Primer, Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 1 #1
      - Recording
        Produced on March 7, 1944, as the opening program in the first COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series. It featured Everett Sloane, Minerva Pious, Peter Donald, Tony Marvin, Ted Di Corsia, Frank Gallop. Lyn Murray composed and conducted the score. On the sleeve's label is written that additional data is in Envelope 84.
        - Movie Primer [disc 1 of 2], 03/07/1944; corwin_0132; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 3)
        - Movie Primer [disc 2 of 2], 03/07/1944; corwin_0133; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 3)
      - Script (84), includes one letter (Box 19)
    - Murder in Studio One
      See also Productions by others: O'Brien, Joel for recorded version, and Productions by others: Weintraub, William Hobart for related material.
      - Correspondence (318), 1948; 1956,; 1960,; 1964,; 1967-1968; mostly permissions (Box 19)
      - Manuscript (318), 1941 (Box 19)
    - My Client Curley
      - Recording
        Broadcast over CBS on March 7, 1940 and presented by THE COLUMBIA WORKSHOP, with the author directing and producing. Kingsley Colton played the role of Stinky; Everett Sloane was the agent. Others in the cast included Peter Donald, Jeanette Nolan, Luis Van Rooten, Jack Knell, Hester Sondergaard, and John Brown. Rymond Scott composed the "Caterpillar Creep" expressly for this program; Howard Barlow conducted the orchestra. A handwritten note on the disc's label indicates that the disc is "Personal copy of Norman Corwin."
        - My Client Curley, March 7, 1940; corwin_0159; Lacquer discs/acetates
          A handwritten note on the disc's label indicates that the disc is "Personal copy of Norman Corwin."
      - Script (322) (Box 19)
    - New York: A Tapestry for Radio, Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 1 #11; Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 2 #4
      - Correspondence (71), 1944-1945; fan mail; production notes (Box 19)
      - Manuscript (304), original, combination of typed and handwritten (Box 19)
      - Recording, French translation
        French language production. Credits, circumstances of production unknown at time of this writing. For more information see corwin_0152 in this collection (original English production) and envelope No. 71.
        - New York - A Tapestry for Radio, French production [disc 1 of 2], corwin_0100; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Disc has no labels.
        - New York - A Tapestry for Radio, French production [disc 2 of 2], corwin_0101; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Side 1 has four tracks, but only two have been digitized.
      - Recording, 1944
        Presented over CBS on May 16, 1944, as the 11th program of the first COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series. Martin Gabel narrated. The musical score was composed and conducted by Lyn Murray. It was reprated [sic] on July 24, 1945, from Hollywood, with Orson Welles as Narrator. Published in UNTITLED AND OTHER RADIO DRAMAS. A note on the sleeve's label indicates that additional data is in Envelope 71. A handwritten note on the disc's label indicates that this is Corwin's copy.
        - New York: A Tapestry For Radio [disc 1 of 2], 05/16/1944; corwin_0152; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 5)
        - New York: A Tapestry For Radio [disc 2 of 2], 05/16/1944; corwin_0153; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 5)
      - Recording, 1945
        Fourth program of the second season. A repeat of the program first done on the first COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series in 1944. This version, starring Orson Welles in the role of Narrator, was broadcast on July 24, 1945. The earlier version is in this collection as LP-54. Published in UNTITLED. Additional data in Envelope 71.
        - New York: A Tapestry for Radio [disc 1 of 2], corwin_0209; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - New York: A Tapestry for Radio [disc 2 of 2], corwin_0210; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Script (71), 1944; second production, starring Orson Welles (Box 19)
    - The Odyssey of Runyon Jones, Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 1 #5
      - Correspondence (76), 1941-1942; 1963-1964 (Box 19)
      - Recording
        A repeat performance, this time with Michael Artist in the role originated by Larry Robinson. Published as one of the plays in THIRTEEN BY CORWIN. Also adapted to a novella-length book entitled DOG IN THE SKY, Simon & Schuster, 1952. Date of the broadcast, April 4, 1944 - fifth program in the first COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series
        - The Odyssey Of Runyon Jones [disc 1 of 2], 04/04/1944; corwin_0124; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - The Odyssey Of Runyon Jones [disc 2 of 2], 04/04/1944; corwin_0125; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 3)
          This record has not been digitized.
      - Script (76), 1941; final broadcast script (Box 19)
    - Old Salt
      - Correspondence (306), 1945; 1948,; 1956,; 1961,; 1964-1965,; 1967 (Box 19)
      - Manuscript (306), 1941 (Box 19)
      - Script (88), 1941; final broadcast script (Box 19)
    - On A Note of Triumph
      See also "Corwin Show For AVO".
      - Recording, Czechoslovakian
        - On A Note of Triumph, Czech production [disc 1 of 9], corwin_0333; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - On A Note of Triumph, Czech production [disc 2 of 9], corwin_0334; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - On A Note of Triumph, Czech production [disc 3 of 9], corwin_0335; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - On A Note of Triumph, Czech production [disc 4 of 9], corwin_0336; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - On A Note of Triumph, Czech production [disc 5 of 9], corwin_0337; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - On A Note of Triumph, Czech production [disc 6 of 9], corwin_0338; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - On A Note of Triumph, Czech production [disc 7 of 9], corwin_0339; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - On A Note of Triumph, Czech production [disc 8 of 9], corwin_0340; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - On A Note of Triumph, Czech production [disc 9 of 9], corwin_0341; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, German, produced by the Overseas Branch of the U.S. Office of War Information
        - On A Note of Triumph, German version Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 09/26/1945; corwin_0236; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - On A Note of Triumph, German version Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 09/26/1945; corwin_0237; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Translation, French, undated; mimeograph copy of typescript (Box 19)
      - Translation, Russian, 1945; carbon copy of typescript (Box 19)
    - One World Flight, 1947
      See also Addresses: Footnote on One World Flight and Speeches: One world revisited.
      Information from donor: "Recordings for this program contain material recorded in various countries during Corwin's journey in 1946 as winner of the One World Flight Award established in memory of Wendell Willkie. Excerpts from these cuts (already excerpted from hundreds of hours of interviews) were used in a preview type of introductory program, the first of a series of 13 broadcasts written and narrated by Corwin over CBS in 1947."
      There were several "work-cut" discs for each program. They represented a third stage in the transmittal of original voices and sounds to the radio audience. The initial recording in the field was made on a wire recorder, the precursor to the tape system that shortly afterward came into general use. As a second step, the entire intake of wire recording was dubbed to tape for editing facility. The third step was to select salient material from hours of tape on each program, and dub these onto 16-inch acetate discs such as the enclosed. Finally, from these work-cut discs ( and not from tape, as is the standard practice today) the recorded material went out on the air, integrated with Corwin's “live” narration, and music The work cuts are in the almost every instance longer than the excerpts heard on the air. In cases where the final selection of the text to be broadcast came within on of the bands on the disc, an engineer in the control room of the broadcasting studio simply had to locate the spot and place the pickup needle on it, ready to go on cue.
      Because portable equipment broke down (wire recorder) studio facilities were used in some countries of this trip, including the Scandinavian. Most of these discs, being on glass bases, have been broken or lost over the years. Naturally, the usable ratio of all such interviews was very small, and particularly so when the interviewee was dull or had difficulty with the language.
      Material on these discs was recorded in Egypt, England, India, Italy, the U.S.S.R., Norway, Australia, Poland, and the Philippine Republic. Most of the material on these discs, including interviews with figures of world renown, has never been broadcast or published in full in any form, and exists on these platters alone.
      - Recording, No. 1 Introduction, excerpts from later programs, to introduce the show
        - One World Flight: Introduction Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 01/14/1947; corwin_0001; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: Introduction Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 01/14/1947; corwin_0002; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 1 Introduction, work cuts
        - One World Flight: Introductory Program Parts 1 and 2 [disc 1 of 3], 01/14/1947; corwin_0068; work cuts; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Side 1 (Part 1): 1 - 1-1; 2 - 1-2; 3 - 1-3; 4 - 1-4; 5 - 1-5; 6 - 1-6; Side 2 (Part 2): 1 - 1-7; 2 - 1-8; 3 - 1-9; 4 - 1-10; 5 - 1-53; 6 - 1-54; 7 - 1-55
        - One World Flight: Introductory Program Parts 3 and 4 [disc 2 of 3], 01/14/1947; corwin_0069; work cuts; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Side 1 (Part 3): 1 - 1-42; 2 - 1-44; 3 - 1-45; 4 - 1-46; 5 - 1-47; 6 - 1-48; Side 2(Part 4): 1 - 1-49; 2 - 1-50; 3 - 1-51; 4 - 1-52
        - One World Flight: Introductory Program Part 5 [disc 3 of 3], 01/14/1947; corwin_0070; work cuts; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Part 5: 1 -1-44 revised; 2 - 1-46 revised; 3 - 1-47 revised; 4 - 1-48 revised; 5 - 1-49 revised; 6 - 1-56; 7 - 1-3 revised; 8 - 1-52 revised
      - Script, No. 1 Introduction (330), 1947; as published in Hollywood Quarterly, with introduction by Jerome Lawrence (Box 20)
      - Recording, No. 2 England
        Describes the transatlantic crossing, and contains interviews in England, including Prime Minister Clement Attlee, Minister Noel-Baker, the novelist J. B. Priestley, Sir Alexander Fleming, Lord Robert Vat Sittart [sic], etc. Statement by Fiorello LaGuardia.
        - One World Flight: England Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 01/21/1947; corwin_0003; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: England Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 01/21/1947; corwin_0004; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 2 England, work cuts
        "Work Cuts"; Disc set includes excerpts from interview with J. B. Priestley, Philip Noel-Baker, Prime Minister Clement Attlee, and others.
        - One World Flight: Takeoff and England Parts 1 and 2 [disc of 4], 01/21/1947; corwin_0075; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. Side 1 has 10 tracks and 8 titles, as two tracks have a grease pen on them; side 2 has 14 tracks and 11 titles as three tracks have a grease pen on them. Side 1 (Part 1): 1 - 3-1A; 2 - 3-1B; 3 - 3-4; 4 - 3-5; 5 - 3-6; 6 - 3-7; 7 - 3-13; 8 - 3-14; Side 2 (Part 2): 1 - 3-15; 2 - 3-16; 3 - 3-17; 4 - 3-18; 5 - 3-19; 6 - 3-20; 7 - 3-23; 8 - 3-26; 9 - 3-27; 10 - 3-28; 11 - 3-29
        - One World Flight: Takeoff and England [disc 2 of 4], 01/21/1947; corwin_0076; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. There is a handwritten title next to each work cut. Side 2 has 7 tracks and 6 titles, as the seventh title is scratched off and one of the tracks has a grease pen on it. Side 1: 1 - 2-5 after take off motor noise; 2 - 2-7 Corwin; 3 - 2-9 Lionel; 4 - 2-11 Hurban; 5 - 2-13 Romaine; 6 -2-14 W. S. Charlie; 7 - 2-16 Landing Shannon; 8 - 2-19 Sounds after landing; 9 -2-20B Noel-Baker (A); Side 2: 1 - 2-21 Noel-Baker (B); 2 - 2-22 Noel-Baker (C); 3 - 2-23 Attlee (A); 4 - 2-24 Attlee (B); 5 - 2-25 Bob W. (A); 6 - 2-26 Bob W. (B)
        - One World Flight: Takeoff and England [disc 3 of 4], 01/21/1947; corwin_0077; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. There is a handwritten title next to each work cut. 1 - 2-27A Fleming (A); 2 -2-28A Fleming (B); 3 - 2-29 Priestley (A); 4 - 2-30 Priestley (B);5 - 2-31 Priestley (C); 6 - 2-32 Bunny (A); 7 - 2-33 Bunny (B); 8 - 2-34A Bunny (C); 9 - 2-34B Bunny (C)
        - One World Flight: Takeoff and England [disc 4 of 4], 01/21/1947; corwin_0078; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. Side 1 label has a different date (01/15/1947) from the sleeve. Side 1: 1 - 2-6; 2 - 2-9; 3 - 2-10; 4 - 2-12; 5 - 2-14; 6 - 2-17; 7 - 2-18; 8 [unreadable]; Side 2: 1 - 2-21; 2 - 2-22; 3 - 2-23; 4 - 2-24; 5 - 2-25; 6 - 2-26
      - Recording, No. 3 France, Denmark, Norway
        Interviews with Maurice Schumann, the scientist Frederic Joliot-Curie, architect Paul Nelson, the poet Louis Aragon, in France. In Denmark, Finance Minister Kristensen, Foreign Minister Gustav Rasmussen, members of Danish Parliament, etc. In Norway, various writers, artists, politicians, Foresign [sic] Minister Halvard Lange.
        - One World Flight: France, Denmark, Norway Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 01/28/1947; corwin_0005; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: France, Denmark, Norway Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 01/28/1947; corwin_0006; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 3 France, Denmark, Norway, work cuts
        - One World Flight: France and Denmark Part 1 of 2 [disc 1 of 3], 01/21/1947; corwin_0089; "Work Cuts"; content unknown; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. On the disc's label the date is different: 01/20/1947 and is written "Part 1 of 2".
        - One World Flight: France and Denmark Part 2 of 2 [disc 2 of 3], 01/21/1947; corwin_0090; "Work Cuts"; content unknown; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. On the disc's label the date is different: 01/20/1947 and is written "Part 2 of 2".
        - One World Flight: France and Denmark Part 4 of 4 [disc 3 of 3], 01/21/1947; corwin_0091; "Work Cuts"; content unknown; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. On the disc's label the date is different: 01/20/1947 and is written "Part 4 of 4". It is unclear if there is Part 3.1 - 2-13 revised; 2 - 2-36; 3 - 2-37; 4 - 2-21 revised; 5- 2-40; 6 - 2-39; 7 - 2-41
        - Band Concert in Tivoli, 06/26/1946; corwin_0350; recorded in Copenhagen, Denmark during One World Flight; includes voice of Lee Bland, who accompanied Corwin on the ONE WORLD FLIGHT journey; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 9)
      - Recording, No. 4 Sweden and Poland
        Interviews with first woman member of Swedish Parliament, Prince Bertil, Swedish newspaperwoman and housewife, etc. In Poland, interviews with President Boleslaw Beirut, Prof. Chizinofsky, scientist Zlotowski, pianist Madame Zofia Rabecwicz, workmen, etc.
        - One World Flight: Sweden and Poland Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 02/04/1947; corwin_0007; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: Sweden and Poland Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 02/04/1947; corwin_0008; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 4 Sweden and Poland, rehearsal
        - One World Flight: Rehearsal of Program No 4, Sweden and Polan) [disc 1 of 2], 02/03/1947; corwin_0050; With errors. Old label reads: "See LP 4 and LP 14-B of this collection".; Lacquer discs/acetates
          (YR66128)
        - One World Flight: Rehearsal of Program No 4, Sweden and Polan) [disc 2 of 2], 02/03/1947; corwin_0051; Old label reads: "See LP 4 and LP 14-B of this collection".; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 4 Sweden and Poland, work cuts
        "Work Cuts"; disc set includes excerpts from interviews with Swedish MP, Prince Bertil, newspaperwoman, housewife and others. In Polish material, excerpts from interview with President Beirut, professors, scientists, pianist Madam Rabecwicz, workers in powerhouse, etc.
        - One World Flight: Sweden and Poland, parts 1 and 2 [disc 1 of 5], 02/04/1947; corwin_0039; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Side 1: Cuts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 - Baroness (YR66106-1); Side 2: Cuts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 - Warsaw Powerhouse (YR66106-2)
        - One World Flight: Sweden and Poland, parts 3 and 4 [disc 2 of 5], 02/04/1947; corwin_0040; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Side 1: Cuts 1 - 5, 6, 7 Powerhouse., Chetto (YR66106-3); Side 2: Beirut, (YR66106-4)
        - One World Flight: Sweden and Poland, parts 3 and 4 [disc 3 of 5], 01/27/1947; corwin_0041; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Side 1: Cuts 1 - 3-30; 2 - 3-31; 3 - 3-32; 4 - 3-33; 5 - 3-34; 6 - 3-35; 7 - 3-36; 8 - 3-37; 9 - 3-38; (YR65906-3); Side 2: Cuts 1 - 3-39; 2 - 3-40; 4 - 3-41; 4 - 3-42; 5 - 3-43; 6 - 3-44; 7 - 3-45; 8 - 3-46; 9 - 3-47; 10 - 3-48; Nelson; (YR65906-4)
        - One World Flight: Sweden and Poland, part 5 [disc 4 of 5], 02/04/1947; corwin_0042; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Side 1: Cuts 1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6; 7; (YR66106-5); Side 2: Cuts 1-4; 5; 6; 7 -8; Zlotowski (YR66170-6)
        - One World Flight: Sweden and Poland, part 7 [disc 5 of 5], 02/04/1947; corwin_0043; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Zlotowski (YR66106-7)
      - Recording, No. 4 Sweden and Poland, unedited recordings of interviews done in Sweden
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 1 of 15], corwin_0301; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Miss Hesselgren, first woman to be elected to the Swedish parliament. She was then about 70. (She is also on discs 2, 10, 11, 15.)
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 2 of 15], corwin_0302; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains between Corwin and Miss Hesselgren, first woman to be elected to the Swedish parliament. She was then about 70. (She is also on discs 2, 10, 11, 15.)
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 3 of 15], corwin_0303; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Mr. and Mrs. Danerius, a couple living in Stockholm (they also are on disc 5, 6, 8, 12).
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 4 of 15], corwin_0304; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and a schoolboy (he is also on disc 9).
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 5 of 15], corwin_0305; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Mr. and Mrs. Danerius, a couple living in Stockholm (they are also on discs 3, 6, 8, 12); and a Swedish farmer living near Uppsala (he is also on discs 9, 13).
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 6 of 15], corwin_0306; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Mr. and Mrs. Danerius, a couple living in Stockholm (they are also on discs 3, 5, 8, 12).
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 7 of 15], corwin_0307; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and a Dr. Andren.
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 8 of 15], corwin_0308; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Mr. and Mrs. Danerius, a couple living in Stockholm (they are also on discs 3, 5, 6, 12).
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 9 of 15], corwin_0309; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and a Swedish farmer living near Uppsala (he is also on discs 5, 13); and a schoolboy (he is also on disc 4).
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 10 of 15], corwin_0310; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Miss Hesselgren, first woman to be elected to the Swedish parliament. She was then about 70. (She also is on discs 1-2, 11, 15.)
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 11 of 15], corwin_0311; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Miss Hesselgren, first woman to be elected to the Swedish parliament. She was then about 70. (She is also on discs 1-2, 10, 15.)
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 12 of 15], corwin_0312; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Mr. and Mrs. Danerius, a couple living in Stockholm (they are also on discs 3, 5, 6, 8).
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 13 of 15], corwin_0313; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and a Swedish farmer living near Uppsala (he is also on discs 5, 9).
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 14 of 15], corwin_0314; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Prince Bertil.
        - One World Flight: Unedited Interviews - Sweden [disc 15 of 15], corwin_0315; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This disc contains interviews between Corwin and Miss Hesselgren, first woman to be elected to the Swedish parliament. She was then about 70. (She is also on discs 1-2, 10, 11.)
      - Recording, No. 5 U.S.S.R.
        Interviews with Serge Prokofieff (Prokofiev), Peter Kapitza, Serge Eisenstein, David Zaslavsky, statement by Michael Borodin, interviews with and music played by Aram Khatchaturian and his wife, interviews with children, members of collective farm, etc.
        - One World Flight: U.S.S.R. Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 02/11/1947; corwin_0009; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: U.S.S.R. Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 02/11/1947; corwin_0010; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 5 U.S.S.R., work cuts
        "Work Cuts"; disc set includes interviews with Serge Prokofieff (Prokofiev), Peter Kapitza, Sergie Eisenstein, David Zaslavsky, a statement by Michael Borodin, uncut music played by Aram Khatchaturian and his wife in Khatchaturian's home; interviews with children, farmers, etc.
        - One World Flight: The Soviet Union Parts 1 and 2 [disc 1 of 6], 02/11/1947; corwin_0028; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Side 1 (Part 1): 1 - Rainstorm; 2 - Jane I (Counting); 3 - Jane II (Alphabet); 4 - Jane III (Song); 5 - Jane (Poem) IV; 6 - Army Boy I; 7 - Army Boy II; 8 - Soprano; 9 - Baritone; Side 2 (Part 2): 1 - Traffic (off); 2 - Traffic (in); 3 - Petroven I (losses); 4 - Petroven II (Greeting); 5 - Petroven III (no war); 6 - Ex-soldier I